stmarys-ca.edu 2019-06-01

# Web Privacy Policy | Saint Mary's College

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Saint Mary’s College of California (“Saint Mary’s,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) will not distribute or sell your information to third-party organizations that has been collected from you while visiting our website (stmarys-ca.edu), unless the form or page to which you are submitting information specifically indicates that such sale or distribution is contemplated.  Please note further, as described in this Policy, that some components of our website are operated by third parties, and thus are subject to additional terms found in the policies of those third parties.  In such cases, there generally will be a link to the privacy policies of the third party, as described later in this Policy.

If you are in the European Union, or if your “Personal Data” otherwise may be subject to the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”), you should understand that we will use our technical infrastructure in the United States to deliver various services to you.  In order to fulfill our contract with you (if you are a visitor to our campus, an applicant, a student, an employee, an alumnus, a donor, a volunteer, a faculty member, a Trustee, and/or you are purchasing items from us online, etc.) we may need to transfer your “Personal Data” to the United States, and possibly to other jurisdictions outside of your home country, as necessary to provide these services.  Similarly, if you are browsing our webpage, we may collect certain “Personal Data” about you (for example, your ISP address) in order to enhance our webpage, and your experience on our webpage.  Processing of your Personal Data as you browse our webpage is necessary for our legitimate interests, and we believe these interests will not interfere with your fundamental rights or freedoms.  “Personal Data” generally means any information that can be used to identify a natural person.  For more information about how the GDPR affects you, [please click here](https://www.stmarys-ca.edu/college-communications/gdpr).

If you have questions about this information, please contact [privacy@stmarys-ca.edu](mailto:privacy@stmarys-ca.edu)

**Information Collected**

While you are using our website, we will only collect your information (such as your name, address, email or phone number) if you provide it voluntarily.  If you do not want this information to be collected by us, please do not submit it.  We will not retain your information longer than is necessary for the purpose for which it is collected , or as otherwise indicated on the page or form on which it is collected.  Information collected on stmarys-ca.edu may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which we (or any service providers) maintain facilities.  Additional details about the use of information that you submit on forms through our website can be obtained from the office or department that has provided the specific form.

Web servers typically collect, at least temporarily, the following information: Internet Protocol (IP) address of computer being used; webpages requested; referring webpage; browser used; date and time.  Saint Mary’s may collect statistics identifying particular IP addresses from which our website is accessed, but does not use such methods to attempt to obtain any personally identifying information.  We use this information solely for internal purposes, such as to improve stmarys-ca.edu and your browsing experience on stmarys-ca.edu.

**Use of Collected Information**

Saint Mary’s may use the information we collect on stmarys-ca.edu for future communications with you (i.e., in order to keep you informed of activities like certain programs and/or special events), but only if you are provided the opportunity to opt out of such communications.

We may use browser-IP-address information to report information about website access.  This information is used to improve your user experience of our website, and may also be used for troubleshooting purposes.  
Some of our website pages may use “cookies” in order to deliver web content specific to individual users.  Personally identifying information (or “Personal Data”) is not stored within cookies.

Our website uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting (“Google Analytics”) to help us understand, in aggregate, the age, gender and interests of visitors to our webpage.  The Google Analytics tool does not reveal your name or other identifying information to us.  Further, we do not combine the information collected through use of Google Analytics with any information that could be used to specifically identify you.  The information received from Google Analytics is used only to improve stmarys-ca.edu, and the type of information displayed to stmarys-ca.edu visitors, so we can better serve those interested in Saint Mary’s.  You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to stmarys-ca.edu by using Google Analytics’ Opt-out Browser Add-on, <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**Distribution of Collected Information**

Saint Mary’s generally will not disclose information collected about you, except for certain explicit circumstances in which disclosure is required by law.

**Access to Own Information**

Questions regarding users’ rights to review, modify or delete their previously provided information should be directed to [privacy@stmarys-ca.edu](mailto:privacy@stmarys-ca.edu?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

**Responsibility for External Sites**

Some parts of our website are maintained or operated by third parties to which we have specifically outsourced such maintenance and operation for the delivery of enhanced services (for example, the athletic information site: smcgaels.com).  You should review the privacy policies of such third parties by visiting the links included within those separate websites, since their policies may differ from this Policy, and they may use the information consistent with their own policies.

**Children’s Privacy**

Saint Mary’s website is not intended for children under the age of 13 and there are no areas specifically set aside for children under age 13.  Nonetheless, we recognize that our website may be of general interest to all audiences and we encourage parents to assist their children if they intend to explore our website.  With respect to information about summer camps and summer programs, the information provided is intended for parents and legal guardians of potentially eligible campers and program participants.  Saint Mary’s requests that any forms or other submissions made in response to such programs be completed by a parent or legal guardian and not the child.  If it appears that we have collected or received personally identifiable information on a child under age of 13 without parental consent, it will not be used and we will promptly delete the information from our files.

**Interactive Features (Facebook/Twitter/YouTube/LinkedIn/Instagram)**

While we strive to protect users’ Personal Data, personally identifiable information, and privacy, we cannot guarantee the privacy and/or security of any information you disclose online through interactive features such as forums, message boards, chat rooms, or similar services (“Interactive Features”).  Please keep in mind when using Interactive Features through our website; you disclose information at your own risk that may be specifically designed to be visible to other users.  You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you choose to submit via Interactive Features can be read, collected, and used by other individuals and/or entities, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit when you engage in such activities.

We also may use Interactive Features and tools, including pixel tags added to this website, that allow data about actions of visitors to be sent to the Interactive Features to track conversions and to allow us to create custom audiences for the courses, products or services we may advertise on these Interactive Features.  We also may provide the Interactive Features with other data we have collected about you for this purpose, using the Interactive Features’ tools that allow data such as email addresses and phone numbers to be locally hashed on our system before we upload and pass such data to any Interactive Feature(s).  The use of such data is governed by each Interactive Features’ applicable privacy policy.

**Your Access to and Control Over Your Information**

You may have the right to access the personally identifiable information that Saint Mary’s has collected about you (contact us at [privacy@stmarys-ca.edu](mailto:privacy@stmarys-ca.edu?subject=Privacy%20Policy) for more information):

•    Opt out of any future contacts from us;  
•    See what personally identifiable information we have about you, if any;  
•    Change, correct, or have us delete any personally identifiable information we have about you; and/or  
•    Express any concern you have about our use of your personally identifiable information.

**How to Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please write to us at [privacy@stmarys-ca.edu](mailto:privacy@stmarys-ca.edu?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or through the postal service at:

Office of College Communications   
P.O. Box 5165  
Moraga, CA 94575-5165  
Phone: (925) 631-4278
